Dovannys Hernández Morales

Quito, Pichincha +593998238819 Movistar dovannys@yahoo.com http://dohernandez.com/home/en



Application Developer with more than 20 years of experience. Prepared for business software development, database management or system assistant (user support) positions across multiple economic sectors. Proficiency in English and Russian languages.

Experience

SEGUROS DEL PICHINCHA. Technological Development Executive

Sep. 2013 – present Quito, Ecuador

Insurance industry. Developing and maintenance of enterprise applications with Microsoft tools: Visual Studio 2019, ASP.NET (MVC), WCF, WEB API, SQL Server.

- Electronic billing project in Web environment.
- Web application for queries of electronic documents of clients.
- Creation of Web services and Windows for the support of own applications.
- Web application for listing and selling Insurance products with Angular.

LOGICSTUDIO. Senior Developer

Apr. 2013 – sep. 2013 Quito, Ecuador

Development of software applications for clients.

- Migration of a billing system. Tools used: SQL Server 2008, Integration Services (SSIS). Client: SALUD S.A. (Insurance Company)
- Modification and realization of Web Methods within Web Services, as well as the creation of a Windows Services application, within the project of sending SMS notifications to clients through a provider. .Net Framework 2.0 C #. Client CREDIREPORT (Financial sector company, Customer credit reports).

INTERGRUPO. Development Engineer

Nov. 2012 – mar. 2013 Quito, Ecuador

Consultancy in information technology for third parties. Development of applications for clients.

- Installation and configuration of a site for Document Management at SEDEMI (Metallurgical infrastructure sector company). Made with SharePoint 2010 on Windows Server 2012, SQL Server 2012.
- Modifications to the Academic Management System (SGA) of the "Universidad Técnica Particular de Lojas" (UTPL), according to the client's requirements. Technologies used: Visual Studio 2010, .NET Framework 4.0, C #, CSLA, Ext.Net, Oracle.
- Installation and configuration of a site for Project Management in PRONACA (Food business). Technologies used: SharePoint 2010, SQL Server 2008, Visual Studio 2010, .NET Framework 4.0, C #, IIS 7.0, SharePoint 2010 Web Services Consumption.

GLOBALWARE.

Sep. 2011 – nov 2012 Quito, Ecuador

Developer

Development of PRODUBANCO's Banking Core. It is based on .NET technology

- NET 2002 (C # Language). Development of client applications Server in n-layers.
- Data base. Microsoft SQL Server 2000 2008.
- Business Intelligence (BI) SSIS.

León y Asociados.

Aug. 2010 - jun. 2011

Developer

Quito, Ecuador

Development of applications for third parties "FERRERO S.A." (Company of the food sector), on technology of Microsoft.

- Visual Studio .Net 2010 (C # Language). Scheduling Workflows over SharePoint.
- Database. Microsoft SQL Server 2008.
- Business Intelligence (BI) SSAS. (Including programming calculations for Data Ware House in MDX Language).

CUBALSE S.A.

Jan. 1997 - sep. 2009

Systems analyst

La Habana, Cuba

- -Programming and attention to the exploitation of systems (Inventory, Accounting, Payroll).
- -Database. FoxPro 2.6, SQL Server 2005, Access 2007.
- -Administration of the network and servers.
- Assembly and maintenance of equipment.
- -Programming of Excel sheets in VBA language (Visual Basic for Applications).
- -Maintenance and Support to Cash Registers (OMRON, OPTIMAL).

CEDAI.

Sep. 1989 – Jan. 1997

La Habana, Cuba

Programmer

-Programming applications in C, C ++ language as well as assembler.

Education

Minsk Sate Polytechnical College

Sep. 1985 – Jun. 1989 Minsk, Bielorrusia

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech), Informatics